Please look at the code mentioned above and please sign up on the Google Cloud.
We've already started making some announcements.
You will likely end up missing the announcements and you'll have no one else to play with.
The second quick logistical announcement is that we'll have an extra lecture on Saturday,
11th Jan at 11am in 1.101.
So a lot of ones over there.
And I think one or two people still have conflict, but in the larger, in the larger
phone we will have almost everyone available, so we'll have to stick with this.
FAQ and the projects which were earlier shared on Google Docs, I'll give all of you a comment
access on it so that if you have any questions, queries, things like what should be the,
what are the maps, what are the main group size you can ask situations if they're already
not there.
Also about projects, if you have any questions, like what is the expectation if it's something
is not mentioned clearly, you can please comment on the Google Doc and we'll get back to you soon.
Also the video and the slides from the first lecture, in order to actually, actually
haven't put up on code translate, which is at the entrance, as mentioned in the slide
above.
This course website has also been now put on Google Cloud.
So you can also get to that.
Before we go forward, we should quickly revise what we started last time.
And someone tell you what is machine learning based on what we learned last time.
We looked at a couple of definitions.
One was from Arthur Sandler, who by the way was the first person to point with the machine learning
and he did that in 1959.
So a long long time back.
Anyone for this machine learning?
The ability to learn without explicitly being to add others, any definition you want to get?
There's a more technical definition also.
But we'll get to that later.
Let's first start with again this same study, same definition of the learning code.
It's a period of study and get computers, they are ready to learn without being explicitly programming.
Okay, anyone tell you what does being explicitly programming here?
Does a need a machine learning involves low programming?
So all programming, assignments are just the ways of learning.
Program itself.
So is it some, some oracle which ends up writing the code?
It's a whole writing program.
Of course there's one area, there's something on the computer architecture, so we're not going into that.
But who I'd say is the machine learning program.
So today's legislative program.
What is the exact meaning of adopting the executive program?
You don't have to replace this.
Okay, can you explain what does mean?
But he's on the right track.
Let's take an example to get this concept even better.
Can you see these model digits?
These are digits from 0 to 9.
And these are from the dataset for in this.
One of the most popular machine learning datasets.
Now the first task for all of us is we want to now write a program to recognize the digits.
And we'll start with code.
Can someone tell me how they'll recognize if a digit is 4 or not?
We're looking at these specific rules.
What does how we add to the code that we need?
Can we start off as 4 can be quantified as a vertical line, a horizontal line, a vertical line.
All of them are jointed.
And then another vertical line going down from the first, from the last vertical line.
Everything of that is that all that is there to 4 or if there are any models.
What about the fact that the height of each of the vertical lines need to be very similar?
Can you write this kind of a rule?
Or do you see a force where one of the lines is very, very long compared to the other?
Generally not.
So you have to report some of these constraints.
But are you done with it anything more?
Just look through the example for do you see any force which would violate the difference
that we've seen it, specify the thought.
And a thought will look that.
Okay, the second last is one case.
What about this one?
Okay, so each of the vertical lines would be a little smaller.
In many cases it would be a, and if I were to write, you will not understand it,
or you will get it.
So because people write different things.
So that's another rule that I like.
Now what do you mean by slides?
Well, it doesn't mean that it can have an inclination of some 10 degrees, 20 degrees, 30 degrees,
very excited, none of them.
So let's say you come up with some number, based on your experience, based on some rules of time.
But is that all?
No, some people write 4 with a star, right?
If you look at this, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5, 4, you have this particular line, we have to join
like this before piloting the end, right?
So that is now another rule that I've written.
You have already come up with 5, 6 of such rules, but that's not all.
Anything else you can think of?
That's why we have not talked about the bits of the lines.
What can we think about that?
Can we cover some rules?
Let's say if I'm writing the different mark or if I'm using the pen in different fashion,
where some of my strokes we fired will be thicker, right?
Maybe that's another particular rule, right?
There can be some cases where the width of each of the stroke is a little different.
You'll have to again capture some of these characteristics, while writing some rules or
writing a program to recognize 4.
So what we have done thus far is explicitly programmed to classify order, right?
So now we understand what is explicit programming, what we know is completely different from this.
So what if thus far does is we had data?
Data was these examples that we already had.
We came up with some rules.
So these were rules which we as experts suggested.
And in traditional programming we have some kind of a pattern, some programming line would be right,
which would recognize all of these.
Of course, what is presented as a vertical line or horizontal line?
Are still higher constructs?
For example, vertical line a program computer does not know what is a vertical line.
So you have to again boil it down to the computer.
What do you think the vertical line to the middle means?
Same.
Ex-axis.
So think of it as pixels and all of the pixels would be of similar shape, like vertically going on.
So we have data rules and traditional programming that gives us the answers.
Now let's go back to the definition.
The genome is a period of study as computers.
We have computers a little bit to learn without being explicit in the program.
And now to make this particular program, to tell me what, if you have to be able to
use traditional programming with machine learning, what do we need to do?
So we are not explicitly programming.
What changes?
The Romans are gone there.
So what we are saying is, I am going to learn with the only explicitly- describe program.
So we don't need the data.
We don't need the answers.
And what we end up with is automatically some function of rules that are being run.
So this is how traditional programming is.
The bad line of the system program is very different from machine learning.
Which I have still done this, done this in a very abstract sense.
We are slowly going to go deeper from this.
We also looked at another definition which was a more formal definition of machine learning,
which was given by Tom, which I like.
Tom is learning from experience E.
If you look at the experience E, tasks, P, and a performance measure, P,
if the performance is improving in the particular task, as to measure by the performance measure.
And it is improving with experience.
Let's say in this particular case, the task is what?
For machine learning.
To classify digits.
And what is the input that is typically given?
You have some, so you said that you have some experience.
The experience can be you have some images along with the true label.
So you have elements like this 0 along with that label that is actually 0.
But you have various different examples.
And the performance measure P, what do you think is the performance measure P?
What do you want to optimize on?
How correctly you are given to classify digits?
So, could you come up with a more scientific sub-centum for correctness?
I can see.
Or similar sub-centum.
So we look at some of these metrics in today.
So we will start of place lecture after having revised what is machine learning.
We will start, we are now starting a company, all of us are starting a company.
And we want to be the basket of those words or some similar words we saw.
We want to scale.
So if you remember one of the keywords which we use a lot in the previous lecture was scaled.
The problem statement is that you want to predict the quality or condition for computer.
Given its visual features.
So we say that our business use cases that growth rates are similar such grocery stores,
they have some human in the loop who looks at each of the tomatoes.
And that is in let's say a per minute per tomato.
So there is a lot of human input involved which is making the whole process look.
We plan to scale it by using computer vision with your features between the data.
So what we are going to do is we have now an assembly line.
You put the tomatoes in the assembly line as the pass of snapshots are taken.
And you automatically classify whether it is a good tomato or bad tomato.
And back of the tomatoes are from away.
Right?
So you are saying that you are saying that you are saying that you are saying that you are
using a huge amount of human effort.
And what are you making your process greater?
So you are saying that why this process we are able to make the living spirit.
Right?
So let's now do one of the machine learning aspect of this problem spirit.
So if you remember that is why I just spoken that there is an enerity of data.
Right?
There is an enerity of experience and data.
So let's say that we have some pass data on the quality of tomatoes.
You have collected thousands of tomatoes and for each of the tomatoes some human expert
quantified whether it is a good tomato or bad tomato.
For now it is just any good or bad tomato talk on the scale of all the tomatoes.
Right?
There are two classes.
Two classes.
What visual features do you think would be useful to characterize the tomato?
Color?
Any...so what...what if they would be a good tomato?
You just...
Which is more red or more...
There is something on the shade of red.
What is the data made of?
Something which is either showing some greenish shade, it may be an anterity.
Black definitely or if it has some fungus or some other attributes.
What is the other attributes which make it a little bit of bad?
It is a shade.
Is it a shade?
It is a perfect surface.
So the...okay some...some...so the size is another attribute.
Let's say that we have seen for now that all tomatoes are roughly over and smaller tomatoes
are bad, very big tomatoes are also bad.
They are very injected with some growth...growth chemicals.
Size, whether we have seen, what are the other things you would typically do?
Fine.
Yeah, but visual features will not look at the people.
So you'll have to get some proxy for that.
So that is another thing which I want all of us to take from the machine learning course.
What are some of the proxy features we could take from?
Yes, texture.
So texture will tell us something about the field of the community, whether it's very rough,
there is more, there is light and etc.
So we looked at these three specific features.
Would there be others?
Yes, there might be thousands of other features.
But for the purposes of this example, it's only these three.
So we were talking about some vast data or some vast experience that we already have.
Maybe it exists in a form of potato like this.
You have some sample, you have the color, size, texture, and you have the condition.
So this condition has been manually and data written down by human expert.
So in this particular table, you think sample number could be a useful attribute of feature
to predict the condition?
How many think yes?
How many think no?
Okay.
Now tell me that it could be a useful feature.
Now think more and more.
How could the sample number be useful?
Sorry.
No, so the equation is orange.
If the other is orange, decide the small, the texture is smooth.
I can roughly say the condition is good.
But does sample number be equal to 1, 10 because the parameters will be equal to 1?
Yes.
1 and 2 are equal to 0.
It sequentially arranged the whole two, so it's not possible to do it.
Okay.
We thought to try to find the data.
But why do you think the sample number could be useful?
So some of you get it to the point that let's say if you sequentially arrange, then we will get something.
But are we getting something?
Yes.
Okay.
So, we'll just try to get it to the point that we can't qualify for.
So, he is answering that maybe there is a notion of time associated with samples, very likely
that could be.
And imagine a scenario where there is one specific time of the year, maybe when all of the variables
are bad, maybe the producer was bad, maybe the leader was making the tomatoes was hot,
had gone wrong, something would have happened.
So, in some very limited cases, the sample number could be used for the feature.
But it's more likely that it's probably better to include more features, which are capturing
the types of things we are looking at.
For example, what was its vehicle condition?
How many hours have passed through the way it was made?
Things like that.
The sample number might be giving them this up.
But then this could be the same example as we saw in the last lecture.
So, the sample number is more likely to be a good feature depending on how we model the
phone process.
So, for now, let's say you know to the sample number, imagine it does not provide any useful
information.
So, then we have some data data which looks like the following.
Okay.
We call this entire table the training set.
And if you noted it, I have labeled them in different colors.
Anyone wants to tell why you are looking for?
Okay.
And put an output as a very technical term.
Any other term you could talk?
There are about these two paths of the so far way.
So, this is the second way to explain it.
Experience and performance.
So, the condition is not very good performance.
The condition is the annotation or the label or the output assigned to this particular item.
So, this is one parameter.
The next one is one parameter.
It's not very good performance.
We call these things as features, item codes, or code gates.
If we go back, let's look at the equation which I was asking.
What features do you think will be used?
Make sense?
These things are called features.
The first three columns in the table are called features.
They are telling us something useful about the termatum.
And then, what is the fourth feature that we have?
It's also the first, where features happen with OVA, if you're all used anonymously.
But you can generally use features that are handy.
OVA is generally used in some of the features.
And the output of the condition in this case is called the output of the response label.
What is the response once you've observed some features?
Everyone, here, till now.
Now, we call this a trading set.
And for now, it produces a bit of populism.
We call this entire matrix as D.
We call this feature matrix.
It contains N samples.
What is N?
N equal to four samples.
And what is the features in this?
The number of features is color, size, and texture, which is three features.
So the matrix X shown in the shader pane is four rows of three columns matrix.
It contains N samples with a RPM, right?
And we can write an individual sample as something like this.
Like X1, we can write as orange, small, smooth.
Or a small, smooth.
Does anyone want to tell you why X1 is written in a column format where in this particular matrix,
X1 appears in a row?
Why?
That is the operation.
So typically, when you consider the features, or you consider a particular sample, you consider
that to be a column vector, right?
So this is where now we started to produce a little bit of annotations.
Each sample is a column vector, which is what I'm interested on.
What is the dimension of this?
P is equal to three in this case, orange, small, smooth, smooth, smooth, right?
That's candidate X as XI transpose where I use from one to n, right?
This is X1 transpose, this is X2 transpose, the third row is, can in fact, the third row is X3 transpose
and X4 transpose, right?
So we are able to now write the matrix X in terms of the individual elements.
So when we have an output vector Y, now this is going to be Y non-
XI transpose, right?
So this way we are able to create this entire training set, the reference size format depending on the Ix sample.
So again, XI belongs to, it's a B M integral vector and Y is an integral vector.
Everyone clear the spot?
Now, the prediction task, this is where machine learning lens is usually right?
If we only had trained set, there is no access used for it.
What you wanted to do was for unseen samples of our scheme for these samples,
for which a human has not yet annotated as a good commit or bad commit.
You want them to be fast in the seminary and the computer vision approach, which there is some camera,
which is looking at these tomatoes, you want to tell what the condition is for them, right?
This is a goal clear to everyone.
So for future unseen tomatoes, of which you don't have a human annotated answer,
you want to tell whether the condition is better bad and then you want to accordingly process.
So we have for these unseen samples that I would draw a line to set very good route.
For these unseen samples, we still observe the input features.
We still observe the color, size and texture as given by the computer vision system, right?
But we don't know the condition. That is what we're trying to do.
Yeah?
We now break this whole matrix into two subsets.
The first we've already discussed is the training set, which we said was the matrix D.
And now we have the test set where we have these specific entities on the condition as unknown,
which we're trying to estimate today.
Right?
So the testing set will be very similar to the training set, but it does not indicate the labels for the output variable.
Everyone clear the distinction between training and testing?
Right?
Okay.
So given the background that we have thus far, could we now tell what we're trying to do from this example in a more succinct fashion?
What do we hope to do given the training set, given the test set?
And we have to have some learning component.
It's the relating line.
How do you relate the input to the output?
I don't need a precise answer, but you can relate.
You can write the output as some function of the input.
Thus far, we don't know what kind of function is this.
And the three algorithms we have are different functions relating the output to the input.
But we want to be able to predict the output using some function from let's say for now.
And where do we learn this F from?
This function F from?
It is.
From the training set.
And where do we apply this function F on?
On the testing set.
So that given this, for this particular sample, given the inputs red, red, and red, you want to predict the condition.
Right?
And the general rule would be that we're able to do this accurately, otherwise it does not make any sense.
Okay, now a big question.
Is predicting on the test set enough to say that the model is invalidating?
Why or why not?
The test set now is missing out the outliers.
Okay?
So we will say that if test set mind is missing out the outliers,
so we can add a little more weight rate.
Okay.
So the answer is the answer that he is giving is that they could be some exceptions.
They could be some outliers.
But that is getting to the right answer.
You need to make a movement.
The case that not the accurate is missing.
The case that it does not have annotations.
So what will it be?
What will it be?
How will you predict the accuracy?
How will we check the accuracy?
Yeah, so we'll come to that.
Bye-bye.
Yes, yes.
Okay.
The test set may be a subset of the brain set and your answer was that the test set might have some outliers.
Both of you are really there.
Can we do some?
Over-thinking.
Let's do.
So we have not thus introduced it on the cooperate.
Can we use some simpler numbers we have seen thus far?
Think of sometimes you might have covered in some probability codes.
Okay.
So the ideal thing that we want to do is to be predicting where all possible inputs.
Right?
The emphasis on all possible inputs.
But can we test that?
Can the test set be all possible inputs?
Maybe an ideal case, yes, but in a more practical case, no, you will never be able to enumerate all possible test cases.
And now relating to the answer, which some of you have already given.
So one way to put it would be that the test set is only a sample for all possible inputs.
Right?
So this now answers or this now relates to the answer we're talking about how high it is.
You could end up choosing a test set which is a very expensive case, a lot of how high it is.
But what can take out why it's which might be present in all possible inputs and also relates to your specific answer that the test set could be a part of the brain set because it's now a sample for all possible inputs.
More generally we have something very simple because there are some or there are some generating process which generates the brain data which I'm calling there as the empirical data sample.
And I've written a technical term here, I do.
So this is identity and independence distributed.
If I would recommend that if you don't know this term again, go back and study some of the great records mentioned.
You sample from the hidden proof or you generate data from the computer process, you're able to get some free data which you'll learn, you'll get a model which in a previous case was some functioned net that we will learn.
Once you've learned by constantly you predict using unseen data, you predict another sample.
So that sample is again also coming from the same data set, from the same underlying distribution of the same generating process by both the data.
So what now we get is that the training set and the effort of samples are from the hidden proof distribution.
Sometimes it's also known as population.
You're getting some samples from the population.
So the test set will not contain all the samples.
In order to say that our model generalizes perfectly, we would have had to see the entire population, which is never the case.
And we have much more deeper differences between the test set and the group population.
Once we study biasing the sample switch, hopefully it will come from the next lecture.
Everyone clear the line?
Okay, so we have last part seen one particular type of machine learning task, where you're trying to classify whether the object or whether the particular the meters would have had.
We now look at a very different example.
We want to predict the analytical data of IT on the other campus.
So again same exercise.
What factors do you think the energy consumption should depends on?
Can you quantify that?
Because whether it's again one specific aspect of IT.
Humanity temperature, okay.
What is the humidity is more?
Do you think the energy is more or less?
More?
Okay, more or more temperature?
Temperature is more, what energy do you want?
Fine.
More and additional cost.
Okay, what are the other factors the capital energy to depend on?
Energy.
Okay.
Then?
Okay, number of people, number of occupants.
And if there are more occupants, do you expect more energy to happen?
Generally yes.
Any other factor?
No.
Sorry.
Okay.
On the side of the airport, there are some other aspects of a campus energy they don't manage.
Right.
We call this a quality term.
Some of them.
Okay.
What are the assets?
It's the energy.
That's the energy.
We can make the parts.
We can make them, but that is in some sense captured by the governments.
Right.
So we want to explicitly write whether something can or we can.
How does that include the population?
Okay.
So the question is how does we can relate with the population?
So I am saying that in some sense when it is a beacon you would assume that many of the
people are let us say not in the maps, but there is a population automatically reduced.
So we say to be beacon population would be lesser than the beacon.
Yes, why you are there?
So you could always come up with some counter events, yes.
But there will be some people who would be leaving, some people who would be coming.
They and I, we can all meet different people.
Okay, so he is saying that the hour of the day is also an important factor.
How can you gain tellers which are expected more than a different option?
So in the end you are keeping, you are taking an objective and you are keeping an end.
So we can assume that for now let us assume that the numbers are 9 people have to 3 x as well.
So in the night time you generally see the lot to be low, at least in the relative comfort
this is very fair graph.
So more people generally more energy, higher temperature, generally higher energy.
Again it can be constructed in a table like this now.
We have people temperature and just for the purpose of the illustration there are only two factors.
People and temperature and energy in kilohertz, if you are having some other unit also.
You could use tools but you know rather more generally, I am certain later.
Now what is the training center?
The first three rows and the considered as prenatured because they have the labels,
also mentioned the output variable or response variable also maintenance.
Whereas the set shown below of the last two samples becomes a test set where the labels or the response variable
or the target level of the function has not been mentioned and this is what you are trying to write.
So you have thus far seen two different kinds of examples.
Let us try and make a little more abstractly because of two specific classes of problems.
I am going to write the first class of problems as classification.
Here in the output variable of concern is discrete in nature.
Does everyone here understand what is discrete?
So discrete means it could be one of few classes.
It could either be a, so one of the examples of discrete is binary whether it is on or off.
It could also be done to be one of three classes.
It could also be minor in the middle of the graph.
Both formerly they say that why I belong to a set from one to see where we have seen classes.
We have seen one example can I even tell you more examples of classification task in my new version.
We have seen that in our state, we have to get the three, three, three.
Sorry, we have to get in.
We need to go to the normal thing.
Who will then?
So the example that is given is you want to predict who will win.
So in fact this reminds me of some very interesting simulation.
So I think there is a very nice log by a late silver.
Those of you who follow sports as well as data, I think should be really looking into that.
And some of these logs is fact greatly winners of the football champions,
the NBA, etc.
You look over the masses.
And they have some confidence with the same who is going to win the league, etc.
So what are the kinds of results you have?
Let's focus on how something is going to happen.
When you also have time, you are going to have to offer a particular basis.
So this is not full class.
And what kind of record features do you think you have to get?
And everyone else can also take this one out.
So if you want to predict whether India and Sri Lanka are playing that, we do not do who will win.
So how will you decide that?
Playing 11th.
Playing 11th?
So you know, by playing 11th, you mean the names?
How do you not?
So some notion of their ratings, right?
All the having said that, only yesterday I read about the very interesting article.
So there was some research paper which mentioned that some of those really chess playing as a play of natural language processing game.
And not looking at the inherent notion of what both means.
So they just gave it a specific, easy, poor, etc.
And that was overly important for all really well-used tasks.
Those of well-wards where they might find this very interesting and frothy.
Okay.
For cricket, maybe we are looking at the player ratings.
Maybe the player age, maybe if it does develop something on that start.
So it's a class case.
Yes.
If there are, yeah, home versus away.
And in fact, if any of you play games like T by Naj, the more you will go that,
they take you to the concentration of the game and they are able to simulate both seasons.
Okay.
Any other tasks, documentation, topic and think of?
End of.
End of the scene.
Okay.
So some of us take an image.
You want to classify whether it's an image or it's an university, it's a round-level thing.
You have not two output classes.
And what is the input that you have given?
No, the input would be an image.
Right?
Input now would be an image of some items embedded.
So, what previously we looked, the kinds of inputs that we had were fitting into the matrix.
So each sample was corresponding to only, you know, let's say P readers.
But now you have a, let's say P cross Q matrix.
So again, you have to figure out how to import the P cross Q matrix into that particular scheme.
Okay.
Okay. Any other example?
Shouldn't we, will it be, will it be trained to follow or it be taught or it will be developed?
Okay.
Will I get a loan or not?
Depending on some, some idea, will I pass the machine or reports or not?
Will I remain away from the kind of lecture or not?
What is the quality of food?
Good, bad.
I think I have multiple such classes.
What grade line in this class?
A, B, C, E, all of the specific question of grade.
This becomes a very interesting topic.
We'll talk about this later.
There is also some notion of ordering associated with grades.
Sometimes you want to provide the data and what.
We're not going to be able to perform.
The second example that we saw fits into something known as regression.
They output variables and t-s in nature, right?
To a large extent, we can assume that.
So we can write yi is a real number.
Okay.
Give me some examples of regression.
You want to predict a real number.
The amount of grades for the data.
So that's the reason.
I think I have the same.
It's a lot of money.
Stop market.
What do you want to predict?
The price of a particular class.
Okay.
Any other example?
That's four.
Sorry.
How many grants of food?
Okay.
How many grants with our teams?
Again, very interesting points of grades of them.
Because again, if you look at all those foods, people have already come up with some foods of the family.
You are only three back to down.
You can get half of the tea, which is never.
You can always verify those foods.
And before we get into the actual algorithms, I wanted to talk about the performance measure fee, which we discussed in the definition.
We talked about experience fee, task fee, and performance measure fee.
I thought it's more important to first understand what different metrics mean.
And what does it mean that we have done for a job in the machine learning or not?
We started with some metrics for class application.
Let's assume that we had a ground growth Y.
So ground growth means the correct labels that we've got.
Let's say we had a particular set of milliliters.
Or the first meter, we know that it was good.
Some human and a different.
Second meter, some unsighted is good and the other three, some unsighted.
Some exodial then is bad.
And then there is some algorithm, some function F that we've learned.
That means of predicting good, good, good, good, good and bad.
And we call this vector as Y-Add.
So we'll use this add a lot of machine learning.
Add generally signifies an estimate.
What is your estimate of these status of the parameters?
So it is Y-Add.
And normal class of the actual running set, for now, that's the thing we have.
Some of them have been demonstrated.
Some of them know the example.
And the prediction is made by the model.
So what are the different metrics we could use to tell whether we have done a good job in predicting?
Perhaps we don't have to answer it.
So, let's start off.
Okay, how many things are you going to do?
Okay, why?
I think we're going to repeat it.
Sorry.
Depends on the answer.
The answer is depends on the state of the art, which is a very valid answer because what is fine to say is that we want to then
recognize the accuracy of the metric that we put up on it.
Just say, I have 80% accurate, that's not mean-edge.
Only if the best report thus far was 60% and 80% accuracy means a lot.
We first look at a very simple metric on the accuracy,
which basically tells us that how many you look at the accuracy across,
why we look at the predictions across specific rows and lists,
and how many times is why I have equal to y,
divided by the length of y-acron.
Right?
So how many times have we accurately or correctly predicted the label?
The accuracy in this case is in terms of proportion is 0.6 in terms of percentage is 60%.
Right?
So it tells you one specific number.
Well, this is often not enough.
And there are different cases in which we need to again contextualize.
Let's look at some specific types of data to motivate the algorithm.
Let's imagine that we have 1.01 samples.
I know you're predicting something which is not a scale of either, which is either word or line.
And we have, and for examples where the ground growth or the actual samples are good, right?
And one sample where the actual quality is bad, right?
Now, there could be multiple cases in which such kind of data-specific.
For example, the cancer screening, you would hope that in most cases,
cancer screening, we will have people's health as well.
They don't have cancer.
Unfortunately, in a very small case, we will be cancer.
But in general, if we look at some data, we will expect it to look something like this.
We will go to good growth cancer, look cancer, look cancer.
Right?
So you end up with an imbalance dataset.
And maybe even with a client-ident, someone is trying to detect problems on imagery or on some means.
Most of the clients will have no client-group-on-group-on-group-on-group-art
or otherwise, you know, people will be getting over twice a period of time.
Now, let's look at a different metric now.
It is called precision.
Let's look at any ground growth, the same table aspect of earlier.
Now, before looking at this slide, can someone tell you what you understand very strong precision?
In general, in this concern, layman comes.
If it is a particular case.
Sorry.
If it is ability or if it is not.
If it is ability, okay.
What does it mean to be very preferred?
If it is.
It is.
It means less, okay.
Any other, or what does it mean to be preferred?
Sorry.
Sir.
What do you mean by when someone asks, can you speak of the client-group?
Or can you write down the term of the product?
Sorry.
Do you think of.
Do you think of precision in terms of whatever you are writing or whatever you are predicting or how to that you mean?
How true that is.
Or how much sense that does mean.
So, more English terms, I mean, layman does it mean that how much sense does it mean what you are writing.
So, now, when you work on the definition, you look at the times you predicted good, right.
You predicted how many times, 1, 2, 3 and 4.
Out of these, 4 times you predicted good.
How many times were you actually good?
Or was the ground growth also sense good, right?
So, you predicted good 4 times, but you will not predict precise in predicting good.
Your precision was thus far, thus, 2 or 4, which is where you are going to find.
Right.
There is everyone getting a definition.
Our precise are you in predicting a particular class.
Now, precision can be defined in terms of the specific part.
You could also define precision for that.
Right.
What is the precision for that?
You have predicted bad once, but for that specific time it was actually not bad.
So, you have got 0 precision in predicting bad.
So, precision for bad could then be 0 or 1 to be 0.
Precision for bad is now 2 or 4.
Right.
Or more technically you would write a fraction of relevant expenses amongst the derivatives.
Now, we come to another method called the recon, which is of failure is the mirror notion.
Now, what is the word English?
What is the English word?
What is the mean that person X has the very good regard?
Right.
You are able to remember, right, something on that line.
So, the definition of the equal is how many times it was actually good?
How much of the, how much of that you were able to recall in a prediction?
Right.
So, it was good, fair, fair, and fair.
I'll, you showed it to the Apple.
We have been able to recall two of these three.
So, three times the definition of the mirror was good.
We have been able to recall two times.
That's the equal is true at the 60 times the
right.
We see a little bit of precision and we got everyone on the P.E. to listen.
Apple again.
We are trying to predict whether tissues cancer does or not.
In the ground truth, we see that we have 100 samples out of which only one of them has
been the answer, which is the last sample, which is shown over here.
And when we are predicting, we predict 99 times that the person or the specific
sample is not cancerous.
And one time, which is the first sample, we predict it to be cancerous.
Right.
So, now let's try and understand the precision and recall for this set of
predictions.
The accuracy of the system is fairly good.
Out of the total hundred times, we were accurate 98 times.
The only two times we're getting wrong is one.
The time, the first sample when we're predicting it to be cancerous,
viral, in ground truth, it is not cancerous.
And the other time we're getting it wrong is when we're predicting it to be not
cancerous.
And the ground truth says it is cancerous, which is the last sample.
So, the accuracy is 98 times.
You've correctly identified one of the hundred times.
Now, let's look at the recall.
Out of the times, the ground truth was true, which is the hundred sample,
only a single sample.
Do we predict it to be cancerous in our prediction system?
No.
Sort of one time where it was actually cancerous, we are not able to recall
that prediction correctly.
That's the recall is 0 or 1, which is 0.
Let's look at the precision now.
Out of the one time which we are predicting the tissue to be cancerous,
was it actually cancerous?
No.
In the ground truth, it was not cancerous.
Thus, the precision is 0 over 1, which is 0.
There is another way to look at the previous example,
which is known as confusion matrix.
We have four entries in this confusion matrix.
The ground truth could be either yes or no, which is cancerous or not cancerous.
And similarly, we could predict to be either cancerous or not cancerous.
We saw previously that out of the 90, out of the hundred instances,
98 times when the ground truth was not cancerous,
we were also able to predict it as not cancerous.
Thus, the entry corresponding to predicted equal to no and ground truth equal to no is 98.
For one instance, if you look at the first sample, the prediction is yes,
but the ground truth was no.
So, the prediction is yes, the ground truth is no, which is the first row and the second column.
And then if we go back, we saw that there was one sample where the ground truth was yes,
but the prediction was no.
So, one sample where the ground truth was yes, the prediction was no,
which is the first column and the second row.
Now, can you think about precision and recall in terms of these quantities or in terms of the confusion matrix?
But before we do that, let us make the confusion matrix more generalizable.
So, we now have four quantities.
We have four numbers which are written as true positive, false positive, false negative and true negative.
Let us try and understand how do we remember these four names.
Let us look at the first true positive.
The ground truth was positive and we are predicting it to be true,
we are truly predicting it to be positive.
Thus, it is truly predicted as positive.
That is true positive.
The first one in the second column is false positive.
So, the ground truth was not positive, but we are falsely predicting it to be positive.
Thus, false positive.
The third element is false negative.
The ground truth was yes or positive, but we falsely predicting it to be negative.
So, it is a false negative and the last entry is a true negative.
The ground truth was a negative and the prediction was also negative.
Thus, you are truly predicting it to be negative.
Now, let us come back to the definitions of recall and precision and try to write them in terms of the four quantities from the confusion matrix that we have just seen.
So, when we talk about precision, we spoke about how correct we are when we predict it to be the positive class.
Let us say yes in this case.
Out of the total number of times we predicted it to yes, how accurate we were.
So, the first row corresponds to the total number of times we predict it to yes.
This becomes a denominator which is true positive plus false positive.
And the portion where we correct is the true positive.
Where we were predicting it to be positive or yes, when it is actually yes.
Thus, the numerator becomes true positive.
Thus, the precision is given by true positive over true positive plus false positive.
Similarly, let us think about recall.
For recall, we said that out of the instances which were true in the ground growth, how many are we able to recall?
So, thus, the instances which were true in the ground growth becomes a denominator which is the first column of this matrix which corresponds to true positive plus false negative.
And the fraction which is identified correctly is the true positive.
Or what we are able to recall is the true positive.
Thus, the recall becomes true positive over true positive plus false negative.
We have another metric called the F score which combines the precision and recall in the following ways.
So, the definition is given by the formula is given by twice precision times recall divided by precision plus recall.
It is sometimes useful to give a single number instead of giving a precision and a recall.
There is another interesting metric called Matthew's correlation coefficient.
The formula looks fairly complicated at this point of time if you see.
But there is one particular reason why this coefficient is very useful.
And to see that specific reason, let us try to work out a simple example now.
For the data that you have given below where the ground growth positive and predicted positive is the largest number 90.
And the other three entries are also in the field in the matrix and fusion matrix.
Can you calculate the precision recall at score and Matthew's coefficient?
Okay, let us talk about precision for now.
The precision is out of the times you are predicting it to be positive how correct you are.
For that we look at the row corresponding to predicted positive that becomes a denominator.
Thus the total entries are 90 plus 4 which is 94.
And how many of them are we correctly identifying that is 90.
Thus precision becomes 90 over 94.
Similarly, if you look for recall out of the entries which were positive in the ground growth that becomes a first column.
That is 90 plus 1 which is 91 entries.
How many are we able to recall correctly? That is 90.
Thus recall becomes 90 over 91.
And we can calculate the F score by twice precision times recall divided by precision plus recall.
Now all of these numbers are giving an indication that we have done a very good job by identification or prediction.
But does this seem to be a problem?
Yes, so the problem is that this was a very very easy problem for classification.
Because most of the instances were positive in the ground growth.
So if you predicted everything to be positive you will have a fairly high precision and recall and accuracy and F score.
But the math use coefficient comes out to be fairly low.
What this is telling us is that you are not doing a substantially good job
identifying or predicting in such a case because the problem itself was fairly simple.
So this is where we need to take all the metrics and all the results with the salt of grain because
it is important to look at how easy or difficult it was when you could have predicted the most occurring class.
I, Grampus has a vector of B number and the prediction will also be a vector of B number.
Right?
We first met with which we look at is called the main squared error.
The way to remember this is to compose the three jobs, main squared error and then we put it in reverse back.
We first compute the error which is y i hat minus y i.
Right?
Predicted minus ground for the i x sample.
You have computed the error and also shown the corresponding error.
Can you see the different colors now?
So y i minus y, y i minus y i tells you the error term.
Then you have a squared term.
So y i minus y i hat minus y i.
For example, you squared the error.
Right?
And then you can find it in the main over it which is the main over the end sample.
Main squared error.
First the error squared is 18 v.
And a term is generally then used in a vector of order group, main squared error which is the root of the main squared error.
Right?
There are another very similar method called the main absolute error.
Again, it starts with the inside the first calculate the error y i hat and y i.
The absolute values of it then take the u.
Right?
We can also come with a vector called the main error.
We just first compute the error and a main over it.
Why is that a parameter?
You use it as a metric.
They would cancel each other out.
If you could have a prediction imagine the number of all 0 0 0 0 0.
Or you have a 4 example of all 0.
And I have predicted as plus and minus and plus and minus.
What is the mean error in this case?
It's mean error is 0.
What is the mean absolute error?
What is the mean for?
Yeah.
I will see you do not want to gain capital.
So this is why it is also what you know what is the metrics.
You are trying to optimize them.
And even if you why you might want to use mean squared error or mean absolute error times.
Right?
There is many things.
There is something more previous, sorry.
It is something even previous.
And you just get a sense of how we use mean squared error.
Okay, so can you tell me how does the RMSC.
So if if by eye hat is very far away from by eye.
Which is going to produce more error.
So, can you say that square others tend to penalize bad predictions much more than the
regular.
So, now let us quickly get into the first algorithm for today.
We are going to talk about decision trees.
We are again now solving a classification problem using a quasi-
tree tree.
We are the algorithm of whether it is sunny or hot or hot or hot, or humidity or the wind.
And whether or not we play it.
So, now you try to predict whether I should or learn a function between data and some of
the attributes of concern.
These are, as we described in the computer, COVID attributes and the output variable.
And this is profit equation because the output variable of concern is discrete.
In this case, it is only in yes or no.
And because I have also used decision trees to follow regression here.
Maybe try to predict the house price given these two properties and each other.
Let us get back to the example which we were discussing.
I am not going to talk about this for now.
So, one of the reasons why I am talking about different trees is started.
We remember last time we were discussing things like over and test the crashes.
Imagine if we are very, very complicated machine learning algorithms.
Let us say some new rental technical problems.
There is often a very, there is often a case of very hard to do,
but it is not really to understand what the model is done.
But the shift trees being one of the very simple models are very, very suited for such cases.
Where you want the model to be educated.
Now, imagine if you go to a doctor, right?
You want to build an application, you want to build a machine learning,
let us say, it adds a screen application for a doctor.
When the doctor tries that, I will provide sigmoid and relu and some phalancy maps
and I have done some attention and 20 other technical terms in the event it works.
Or let us say that I have come up with a set of rules.
If the patient has, you know, decaying cell function and patient has some swelling etc.
Then the patient is like you have to ask them, which of them do you think is a doctor?
Let me show you a couple.
Probably the second one, right?
Because that is called interpretive. This is also about many of those things, right?
If we go back to this example and if you think in your life, if you were to play tennis,
what does this kind of guy in here is very clear.
One, I don't know if it is just not clear, it is a very clear thing.
It cannot play against the world.
But then of course, you not want to play with this very hard.
You not want to play with it very human.
Looking at this, playing a meetup of a specific example,
can you tell me some of the times you will definitely play an operator.
As I have played in the overcast, I will always play.
I mean, tell me something like that.
Okay, in fact, when it is overcast, you see, you are not clear always playing, right?
Just look at these specific roles.
So can you tell me how the taste and pull kind of rules?
If it is overcast, I will definitely play.
If it is not overcast, it is semi.
And let's say that the temperature is mild, then I will also play.
Right?
This is how we find to play a real structure, which is the idea of output of the difference between people.
So this is what we both learned from machine learning, as well as called different languages.
So there are three.
You can see you have some rules, you have some branches, and you have some rules.
These are also telling you what is different.
I will be stopping you, basically, if it is overcast, you will always play against.
If it is, if the output is overcast, you play against.
But if the output is semi, and the humidity is lower, it is still clear.
It is only when the humidity is high, and the output is sunny, I will not only play.
Similarly, if the output is raining, but the wind is weak, I can still play.
But if the wind is strong, maybe I will not be able to play.
Or this specific example.
Right?
So this is what we hope to learn using our own model.
We have data, we have some performance images, what the accuracy of the fields are, and we
have experience coming from this data.
So interestingly, what is an optimum decision tree that we can learn?
So what is the optimum tree that we can learn?
We have learned one such tree.
Could you have learned many such trees?
Could you have learned tree where the output appears above one of the attributes appears
below?
So there is a very old table.
Does everyone recognize the same?
Rather, M is the best.
Where have you started?
Cial, Cial, R is, which is your regarding book.
It is by the same author of this clause, published in the 19th century.
Where the measure of constructing optimum binding to this tree is NP-complete.
Which means that we can have so many different trees, we don't, it is non-driven to tell
which is the best.
This is a
one of the purpose of the specific, let's say that kind of data.
It cannot be done primarily.
So we need some of the solution to tell which is a good tree.
That is the objective to end up creating good tree.
And which is good in the same way to classify or it is able to predict after it.
But we cannot enumerate all those things.
So we end up using something called say, greedy algorithm.
So greedy means literally greedy.
And the intuition is that at each level of the tree, we choose an attribute that gives us
the biggest estimated performance gain.
We are looking at some performance standards.
We want something which is given as the best performance gain, but we are only able to
estimate it.
We are not getting the entire accurate performance gain, we cannot get that.
But greedy algorithms can be really bad.
Imagine that this is you, you want to now, you know, you are very impatient.
You want to reach them early, you are very concrete.
You see that there is no car over here.
You try and over there, you try and take a left.
And then you, because you have only seen the same spot, you are not able to see this, these
huge tracks.
You take a left over here and then you perpetually caught behind these various global interactions.
They are moving at 30 degrees.
It will have been better if you have just stayed at this point, right, in the long run.
So what we have done here is to take a very greedy position.
Right?
We have not considered the global picture or we have not seen very much into the future.
We have just seen what is the best I can do right now, which is just take a left and then
I will be caught in these global tracks.
So this is just to show that media is not off there.
Now we come up with the first algorithm.
This particular algorithm is called IDP of some of the variations of this particular algorithm.
We have created three specific arguments.
The first is examples, target attribute and arguments.
Can anyone tell me what you think the target attribute is?
The output.
So the output, how we target it is what the response variable or the output variable will actually
tell us somehow.
What do you think are the outputs?
The features here, which were outlook, invent, mutation or those specific features.
What are the examples?
Examples are the set of, examples are basically the matrix that we have.
Which contains the target attribute, sample and arguments.
We will start with the algorithm by grading root node.
In the previous case, we wrote the first cause outcome.
We will first of all this in Sanskrit with an empty root node.
So say that if all the examples are positive or negative or yes or no,
then return the root to the label class and make it as clear.
You understand what this means.
So if all of the examples, if all of the examples were yes or no, do we need a
decision to be a candidate or a candidate to be a decimal?
You can always predict it to be yes or no.
There is no decision involved.
There is no specific attribute to this telling you any, you are all this limited.
If all the examples, if the attributes is empty, then return root to the most common
value of target attribute and examples.
We will come to this later.
But for now, let's look at the recursive procedure.
This is a very nice, intuitive algorithm which can work with the algorithm.
You first pick up an attribute, a, which best classifies the example.
Now if you go back to this tree, we pick the first attribute that's output.
So the inclusion for that outlook will help us get the best estimated performance gain
or does the best attribute, does the best attribute for classifying the examples.
How does the notion of best coming will look at an adventure?
Now the output A was chosen as, the attribute output was chosen as A.
What are the values that they are, attribute output, output, take?
Sunny, sunny over task or rain, right?
Now for each of these attributes, can it call the same concept because of any time?
That is the simple solution to the algorithm.
At each level, you keep on taking the same variable.
That's, so we set the root to be K and for each value of A, which was sunny, sunny, over task and rain,
you then add new pre-branch and you also reduce your number of examples from now, right?
You restrict the set of examples where the attitude A was the particular value of B.
And the examples is empty, you add B to the label of most common value of content.
Otherwise you call the same procedure.
After having removed the set of attitudes on the remaining subset of the way.
So this is how we complicated just code on commit, we'll get into the details of it.
But before that, we had talked about having the best estimated performance gain, right?
How do we quantify that?
So we come up with a metric of the common with the side-style measure known as entropy.
What do you think entropy means in general?
You would have started from the phenomenon.
So randomness or some impurity in sample.
If you see a set like this, can I tell you what is the entropy of this?
Randomness or disorder or the amount of unclarity?
Do you know the formula? Have you studied the formula of entropy?
The definition of entropy is given, you have five rows and nine rows, right?
Imagine all of these ODEs were yes, right?
We have an disorder in the system.
You have anything which is uncertain.
No. So then in such cases we will say the entropy is zero.
Right? If the answer was seven, yes, and seven rows, what could you think is the entropy?
So it would be very high, right?
Because you are very unsure about whether it should be a yes or a no.
So the formula is given in terms of minus p log, in salvation minus p log p, for the different classes.
We had probability of no as 5 by 14, we had 14 examples, 5 of which were no.
And I know that they were yes, and log base two probability of no.
So if you do this calculation, it comes out to be 0.9.
This is the daily high number.
We also get a curve by this.
So the probability of yes was zero, the entropy is zero.
Right? So this means that there is no disorder in all the examples in the data.
And if you look at the other extreme, the probability of class or yes is one, there is again no entropy
because there is no uncertainty in the system.
The maximum uncertainty or ability happens when the probability of class is the same as probability of no.
Right? So we will start up with calculating an entropy of a set.
And we now what it is to use an attribute A, which is able to give us the biggest performance gain.
So can you think of in terms of starting with entropy as a starting point?
What manipulation or what are the statistical measures we need to tell this is the best attribute?
Okay, but how do you calculate the entropy of an entropy?
So again, to think of it in terms of we have to choose an attribute.
So before it is started up with the elementary learning, you have several examples.
You can calculate the entropy of that sample.
Now you want to choose an attribute which will lower the entropy.
Right? So basically if we go at this point.
So we said that there was a lot of uncertainty in whether I will break into some more.
Right? Which means that there is a lot of memory.
But if I choose output as over class, I know that I will get an entropy in later.
So there is no element of entropy involved there for those specific examples.
So we will now see that we are trying to choose an attribute.
Subject will choose an image. The entropy becomes lower.
Right? There is a disorder in this system.
So that concept is known as information gain.
I just look at the, I just show the formula.
Information gain is known as the formula is given in terms of regression entropy.
By partitioning a set of examples, S on an attribute.
So an attribute is taken from different values.
For example, the output traffic in sunny, rainy or over class.
We then write the gain on a set of examples S.
Subject on an attribute A as defined by the entropy which is the initial system.
Of all the examples, minus the weighted entropy is weighted by the number of samples we have for the particular value.
But in fact, in the entropy of the subsets that we have written.
Right? I will not go into the details but now let us assume that at this point of time
we have four days examples.
We choose an output as the first known.
The entropy of this set is zero.
The weighted entropy of this set is also zero.
This side will have some weighted entropy.
Let us stop at this point with the input.
We have to understand that we are trying to choose an attribute which reduces the entropy.
Let us speed at 11am on our pattern.
.